A Guide to the Papers of Amanda E. DeHart, 1920, 1989
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Amanda E. DeHart Papers, 1920, 1989
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1988-61
The Amanda E. DeHart Papers contain correspondence, photographs, tapes, and artifacts. Much of the material relates to Christiansburg Industrial Institute. There is also a self-portrait of J. Rupert Picott.
Amanda E. DeHart
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Amanda DeHart, a graduate of St. Paul's College in Lawrenceville, taught cosmetology at Christiansburg from 1952 until 1966. In 1976, Mrs. DeHart and a number of other individuals formed the Christiansburg Institute Alumni Association. Mrs. DeHart was a native of Pulaski County, attended both the Calfee Industrial School and Christiansburg.
In 1988, Mrs. DeHart gave to Virginia State University her papers, many of which document the History of African American Education in Southwest Virginia. Mrs. DeHart and James W. Smith, professor of History at Virginia State University co-authored The Christiansburg Institute: A Proud Heritage in 1991. Additional material about Christianburg may be found in the: John Banks Papers cc. # 1984-34, The Christianburg Alumni Association Papers Acc. # 1988-62, The Colson-Hill Family Papers Acc. # 1965-13, The VTA Papers Acc. # 1969-14, and The VIA Papers Acc. # 1969-37 all may be found in the Virginia State University Special Collections Archives.
Mrs. DeHart was the historian and Archivist for the Christianburg Alumni Association and her papers follow her arrangement.
Scope and Content Information
The DeHart papers are an interesting mixture of correspondence and three dimensional items documenting education for African Americans in Southwest Virginia during the era of segregation.
Series Description
Series I. Items Collected by Mrs. DeHart Correspondence, Printed materials and other collectables of Mrs. DeHart.
Contents List
- Items collected by Mrs. DeHart
  - Correspondence- General (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Correpondence- Christianburg Industrial Institute (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Correpondence- Christianburg Industrial Institute (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Audrey and Nerrisia Long Papers (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Collectables (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Calfee Junior Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 1:6)
  - St. Pauls College Memorabilia (Box-folder 1:7)
  - St. Pauls College Memorabilia (Box-folder 1:8)
  - St. Pauls College Memorabilia (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Calfee Memorabilia (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Awards (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Self Portrait - J. Rupert Picott (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 1:14)
  - The Ram -Yearbook 1967 (Othertype 2)
  - Golden Tigers- Yearbook 1963-1964 (Othertype 2)
  - "Pulask is for birds"- Car Plate (Othertype 2)
  - The Golden Tiger- Yearbook 1955 (Box-folder 2)
  - Notepad- Hair Weev Association (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Va State Board of Barber Examiners- Rules and Regulations 1963 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Vocational Industrial Ed. Dept -- Test Booklet (Box-folder 2:8)
  - The P.I. Instructor Pamphlet (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Virginia State Board of Registered Professional Hairdressers- Pamphlet (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Christina's "Snap Ons"- Pamphlet (Box-folder 2:11)
  - National Beauty School Journal July, 1971 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Guides for the Beauty and Barber Equipment and Supplies Industry- Pamphlet July 11, 1968 (Box-folder 2:13)
  - Johnston Memorial Library - Pamphlet (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Hair-Weev Pamphlet (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Christianburg, Virginia Inventory (Box-folder 2:16)
  - The Talisman Newspaper April, 1948 (Box-folder 2:17)
  - The Tiger Beat Centennial Issues April, 1980 (Box-folder 2:18)
  - The Student Journal (Box-folder 2:19)
  - The Spartan Newspaper Nov 3, 1971 (Box-folder 2:20)
  - The Viking- Loudon Valley High School Newspaper (Box-folder 2:21)
  - VEA News Feb 1970 (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Autograph Book (Othertype 2)
  - Seven Alumni Meeting Tapes (Othertype 2)
  - Scrapbook (Othertype 2)